[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
HAPPY CENTENNIAL,
POBLACION ARDIENTE!
[host] Let's all give
a warm round of applause
-for the Ardiente family!
-[applause]
[man] Ma'am, someone asked me
to give this to you.
[Emilia] This is impossible.
This is not happening.
You're dead.
[Lily] You're right, Emilia.
Ivy Aguas is dead.
[Julio] If anyone dares to take
this province for themselves,
they will answer to me.
Because the truth will always,
without a doubt, prevail!
Viva Ardiente!
[in unison] Viva Ardiente!
[Lily] This is justice
for Poblacion Ardiente!
No matter how high
you've exalted yourself,
I, Lily Cruz,
will drag you down
to where you truly belong!
-[Raul] Arnaldo!
-[Emilia] Arnaldo!
[Camia] I never thought
this day would come.
[Lily, crying] This is my victory.
To finally be with you.
The two of us together,
along with everyone I love.
[Emilia] You can post your bail,
but you can't return
to being a governor again.
Papa, you're so doomed. You are so doomed.
[soft piano music playing]
Lily.
Why did you bring those things out again?
I just really missed Dad again.
The Ardientes may have gotten
what they deserved, but…
it would've been better
if Dad were still with us today.
I remember all the things he did for me.
This was our favorite book, remember?
Every night,
he would read this to me.
Ever since then…
he's been an inspiration to me.
Lily…
I'm sure your father's
smiling down on you from above
because you've grown into such a brave
and determined woman
with a good heart.
[sentimental music playing]
I did not hire you to give me excuses!
Just go do your job!
Papa, calm down.
Why are you so stressed when you
just got out of the hospital?
-What if you get a heart attack?
-[slams table]
It's all that Lily Cruz's fault!
Oh, Papa. I've been telling you for ages
that Ivy Aguas and Lily Cruz
are the same person,
but you wouldn't listen.
This is just another case
of "I told you so."
Emilia, you're worried
I'll have a heart attack, right?
So, why does it seem like
you're making me even angrier?
And besides, who do you think
is responsible for incurring
that woman's wrath?
Isn't it you?!
-No!
-[Julio scoffs]
You're the one who had
Lily Cruz's father killed,
and later on, had her mother raped.
Then, you insisted
on killing Lily Cruz herself!
But, lo and behold, what happened?!
Now, she's alive and out for revenge!
[inhales deeply]
Therefore, you should be blamed
for whatever misfortune
befalls this family.
[gloomy music playing]
[exhales sharply]
[knocks on door] Papa?
Papa, I heard you shouting
from outside. Shouldn't you be--
Oh, shut up! You're another one to blame!
You are at the very heart of this mess!
The both of you.
[Emilia clears throat]
You attempted to kill Lily Cruz's family
many moons ago, but you failed!
Do you really want me
to teach you the proper way
of disposing of troublemakers?
Papa, with all due respect, but…
don't you think someone
looking for revenge
was bound to happen? I think so.
Excuse me?!
Well, you know…
Let's face it. To be frank, Papa,
this family has ruined
so many people's lives,
not just Lily Cruz's.
There are tons of people
who'd want to make you pay.
So, if you ask me, I really think
we should just calm down
and stop fighting each other.
Or else, we'll only cause
this family's downfall.
[clapping] Wow!
Since when did your little black
heart develop a conscience?
Well, let me remind you.
Weren't you the one
who kept Camia Cruz alive?!
And yet, you get to go away unscathed!
-Huh?!
-Papa.
-No!
-Papa!
-Papa, no!
-Calm down.
-You know what? Just get out.
-[suspenseful music playing]
Just get out.
[Raul mumbles]
Both of you. I said get out.
[exhales sharply]
[breathing heavily]
[groans]
I will never forget the name "Ivy Aguas."
After all,
she's the one who fought all the pain
that Lily went through.
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
Well, not all of Lily's memories were bad.
She's had some good ones too. Right?
But for now,
you need to let Ivy Aguas go.
Be Lily again. Embrace your true identity.
You're right, Jepoy.
Ivy Aguas' mission has come to an end.
"Ivy Aguas" was just a name.
That strength and courage to
fight against the Ardientes…
I know that was all Lily Cruz.
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
[Diego flicks lighter]
Dad.
Dad, thank you
for guiding me.
Even now,
all those lessons you taught me…
I still keep them close.
You taught me how to value life
and morality.
I wish you were here, Dad.
I wish…
you were still here.
I love you, Dad.
I love you.
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
Nanny Carlotta,
I miss you so much.
Nanny…
I finally got the upper hand
against the Ardientes.
And if you were here,
I know you'd tell me…
how happy you are for me.
Nanny…
Thank you.
Thank you for loving me,
and for taking care of me.
It made me stronger each time.
[Lily sniffles]
I love you so much, Nanny.
[sniffles]
I'm sorry I wasn't there.
I love you.
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
[Lily] Ms. Prianka…
You gave me a second chance at life.
You taught me…
how hard you should strive
for what you want.
You even taught me how to run a business.
You taught me
how to be strong.
To be strong
so that I could find justice.
Ms. Prianka, I know…
how you were always there
for all my battles.
I know you're always with me.
Thank you…
for taking me in
and treating me like your own.
You gave me your name.
[sniffles]
You named me "Ivy Aguas."
You taught me how to fight back.
And I'll never forget
everything you taught me.
[sniffles]
I'll never ever forget all the efforts
you made to teach me.
I love you, Ms. Prianka.
Thank you so much.
["Wildflower" instrumental playing]
[whispering] Thank you. For everything.
Hi. Good morning, Papa.
Good morning.
[groans]
Wow! I can smell breakfast
from my bedroom.
This is nice.
I'm so hungry, I could eat a horse.
-Okay.
-Oops. Papa, wait.
This is not your breakfast.
Hold on. Jenny!
-What?
-Jenny!
What do you mean this is not my breakfast?
Yes. We prepared a special
breakfast for you, Papa.
There.
What is this?! You expect me to eat this?
This is what makes people sick.
Papa, stop complaining.
You have to live healthy.
Remember? And eating
healthy food will help you.
I don't want you to die. When you do,
you'll be forgotten.
It's not your time yet.
[Julio] Stop it!
[Emilia] Eat, Papa. Come on. Fruits.
[Julio] What?! What's this?! What the--
-Papa.
-What right does this--
That's enough. There you go again.
Be easy on your heart.
Stop it. I know you want
me healthy, but stop it!
You don't have to be rubbing it in.
[newspaper thuds]
-You're so grumpy today.
-[Julio groans]
Oh, the attorney's here.
-Attorney, good morning.
-Good morning, Governor.
Please, please give me some good news.
Make my day, please.
You'll want to hear this, Governor.
Their opposition
to your bail posting got denied.
[gasps]
So, it means I remain free, right?
-Yes.
-[Julio laughing maniacally]
I knew it!
I am Julio Ardiente,
and I always get what I want
no matter how big or small.
-And this is mine.
-Papa!
You're not supposed to eat that.
[taunting]
[muffled laugh]
Unbelievable.
[moans]
[Emilia] Join us, Attorney, for breakfast.
[security guard] Careful.
Take that directly to the storage room.
-Hurry up.
-Hey!
What are you doing?
[security guard] Excuse me, sir.
You're not allowed here.
Are you out of your mind, boy?
Do you know who I am?
I am Governor Julio Ardiente.
[tense music playing]
-I'll handle this.
-Yes, sir.
-Disrespectful--
-Julio.
Last time I checked,
you had a problem
with your heart, not your head.
So, why is it so hard for you
to understand the law?
Or… Or is it just old age?
Stop playing house in my territory.
I'm not playing house.
This is the house
of the governor and that's me.
I am the governor.
[laughing]
[tense music playing]
[Julio sighs]
Here's a letter from the
Office of the Ombudsman.
[tense music playing]
[Julio] "90-day suspension."
What am I? A student?
I won't let a stupid letter
tell me what to do.
You do know what you're doing
is illegal, right?
So, if I were you,
I'd avoid trouble and leave.
You know, even if I were
to build an office
at the entrance of this capitol,
there's nothing you could do about it.
No one can stop me. No one.
Suit yourself.
[tense music playing]
[crowd chanting] Governor Julio!
Governor Julio! Governor Julio!
[Lily] No matter how high
you've exalted yourself,
I, Lily Cruz, will drag you down
to where you truly belong!
[Julio] You can't do this to me!
I am Julio Ardiente!
[tense music playing]
[music stops]
Raul is just so reckless.
How can he possibly believe
that Papa will change?
Seriously? Does he think
this is a fairy tale
where the evil villains
learn their lesson at the end?
No way!
[in distorted voice]
If that's the case, Emilia,
why did you defend him from Julio?
You should've just let him die.
Because I don't want any more commotion.
This situation's already a mess.
Wait. Why are we talking
about him, anyway?
Now that Julio's done for,
Emilia, you should join me.
I'll make you my queen.
You'll be Jaguar Queen.
-Jaguar Queen?
-Yes, Jaguar Queen.
I'll treat you like a queen,
as will my people.
We'll do nothing, Emilia, but get rich.
We're now free to do that
because Julio's over.
No more competition.
[tense music playing]
But, Jaguar, that's not the life I want.
I want to be the queen of Ardiente.
And you will be, Emilia.
As long as our operations are successful.
They'll all bow down
to the queen of Ardiente.
[tense music playing]
I am Lily Cruz.
I pretended to be Ivy Aguas
because I wanted to seek justice
for my family,
and for everyone who was abused
by the Ardientes.
I secretly sabotaged our enemies.
And I secretly helped Diego's camp.
Diego and I, along with my family,
will be the bridges connecting you
to the new government
of Governor Mateo Ruiz.
And I, as one of the owners
of one of the biggest
realty companies in the country,
truly want to help and support you.
[cheers and applause]
[supporters chanting]
Lily Cruz! Lily Cruz!
Lily Cruz! Lily Cruz! Lily Cruz!
Please, you don't need to do that.
-I'm not campaigning.
-[chanting continues] Lily Cruz!
-Lily Cruz! Lily Cruz!
-I just want to help.
-Please.
-[chanting continues] Lily Cruz!
Lily Cruz! Lily Cruz! Lily Cruz!
[Lily] Attorney.
Good morning, Lily.
I've taken care of your papers.
You are now back to being Lily Cruz.
[poignant music playing]
Thank you, Attorney.
That includes all
your documents for Aguas Realty.
But I really think
you should go there personally.
All right. I'll see to it.
Please sit down.
It feels so good…
to be Lily Cruz again.
It feels so good because
I no longer have to mingle
with the people I despise,
such as the Ardientes.
I no longer have to keep up pretenses.
Others may think it's as easy
as playing a game.
But it's not. It was never easy.
Ivy Aguas was a very brave woman,
a courageous mask I hid behind
and held on to.
Because I knew
that under the guise of Ivy Aguas,
I could protect myself from the Ardientes.
[sighs]
But now that they know the whole truth,
I'm sure they're itching
to exact revenge on me, on you,
and all of my loved ones.
Lily, you'll have to fight them
head-on from now on.
[suspenseful sting]
We know that, and we're ready for it.
At this point, you've already
sacrificed so much
for this fight.
And it's time for you to be happy
by being Lily Cruz, by being true.
I know that's what will make you happy.
You deserve to be happy, dear.
Thank you, Mom.
Anyway, go ahead and eat.
Attorney, please.
Um…
I'll just meet up with Governor Ruiz.
I'm supposed to give him my proposal
regarding Poblacion Ardiente.
-Attorney.
-Take care, dear.
[Lily] I will, Mom.
[spritzing]
[sniffs]
That smells nice. Going out on a date?
Um…
Can you please stop
sneaking around like that?
You haven't answered my question.
Okay, Raul. First of all,
I'm not going out on a date.
Second, I don't think
I have to answer your question
because lately, you've had
nothing good to say to Papa.
-So, just keep quiet, okay?
-[scoffs]
You know, I'm honestly surprised
that you're still alive at this point.
That's all because you defended me.
Don't get any ideas, Raul.
Frankly, I pity you. I have to go.
I'm asking you. Who are you meeting?
The governor.
Why? What's your business with him?
Well, you know, Raul,
I was once the queen of Ardiente.
And I am an Ardiente.
So, since Papa has been
unseated as governor,
I'll just prove my worth
that I can still be the queen.
So, if you'll excuse me,
I have to meet with the governor.
[soft piano music playing]
Diego.
Lily.
Ma'am, we'll get going.
You two take care.
Stay safe.
-[Diego] We will.
-[Lily] Bye, Mom.
[Camia] Bye.
[soft piano music playing]
[door closes]
I want you to review all the
-former governor's contracts.
-Ma'am, he's still in a meeting.
[Emilia] Hi, Governor.
Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
Do we have an appointment?
Now we do, Governor.
Um, gentlemen, will you please excuse me,
so I can fill in the governor?
Gentlemen, can you give us a minute?
-Sure.
-Yes, sir.
-Excuse us.
-Thank you.
Whatever it is, make it quick.
As you can see,
I'm in the middle of a meeting.
So, you like it fast, Governor.
You know, I admire you
for standing your ground
against my papa.
You see, my father still thinks
he is the king of Ardiente,
when in fact, his time is really over.
Can you get to the point?
I want to make a proposal, Governor.
An offer.
I want to be part of your administration.
You see, I'm a former mayor
and governor of this place.
We can help each other a lot.
Governor, I may be an Ardiente,
but the truth is,
we're both victims of my father.
So, if I were to become part of your team,
we'd make magic.
All kinds of magic, Governor.
[suspenseful music playing]
You may leave.
[Emilia breathes deeply]
[suspenseful music playing]
-Governor.
-[Lily clears throat]
Ivy!
It's Lily.
Whatever. Um, Ivy, Lily…
[hissing]
They both sound like
a hissing snake to me.
You know, all this time,
I thought we were friends.
Almost sisters, even.
But little did I know,
you only came here
to take revenge on my family.
You have no right to reproach me,
Emilia Ardiente.
In fact, your soul isn't enough to pay
for all the horrible things
you did to my family!
Why? What are you going to do to me?
Have me killed? Have me raped?
No matter what you want for me,
you can't seem to make it happen.
I mean, look. Look at me now.
I'm still here, aren't I?
And even though we're no longer in power,
I can still make your life miserable.
[suspenseful music playing]
Just accept it, Emilia Ardiente.
Just accept that both you
and your family have lost.
Poblacion Ardiente may be named
after your family,
but let me tell you this.
While I'm still alive, Emilia,
I won't let anyone in your family reign
over Poblacion Ardiente ever again.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Emilia] Diego, get her
iced water so she can chill.
So grumpy today! Huh!
[suspenseful music playing]
I plan to put up a media complex.
Media complex?
Yes. The media complex
will house a tech college,
call center, learning center,
and other venues
for learning and improvement.
And where will you get funding
and sponsors?
Mr. Keng, those two things
won't be problems at all.
I will personally ask certain
parties for their support.
This project will create
opportunities for employment,
and advancement in technology
for the betterment of Poblacion Ardiente.
Your proposal sounds great, Ms. Cruz.
It will surely benefit our province.
Thank you, Governor Ruiz.
And I really count on your full support.
Everyone's support.
So, you're telling me that Ivy
isn't really Ivy Aguas?
You're telling me that she is Lily Cruz?
Yes, ma'am.
That's crazy.
For someone who brought down
the whole Ardiente empire,
she's named Lily Cruz?
[laughs]
That's such a weak name!
[chuckles]
She sounds way too innocent.
[inhales sharply]
Is she the one you were helping?
Is that why you were always away?
Ma'am, you know I can't just leave them.
Why do you waste so much time with them?
Well, now that the Ardientes
have lost their power,
now is the perfect time
for us to put up our own empire.
You and me.
[foreboding music playing]
I can be queen, and maybe…
you could be king.
Ma'am, don't.
You know it's pointless.
I don't want to join any gang
or take part in any of your plans.
Stop bugging me. I don't need you.
Are you sure you don't need me?
So, why are you here?
Did they reject you?
Did they make you jealous?
Or… you just want to de-stress?
Whatever your reason is, I don't care.
What's important to me
is that brought you here.
That's why I'll never let you go.
Never again.
[dark sensual music playing]
Ma'am.
[breathes deeply]
Ma'am, hold on.
Ma'am!
[Jepoy exhales sharply]
[footsteps departing]
You can throw a tantrum
all you want, Governor.
But that's not going to help.
And what do you expect me to do?!
I advise you to wait it out.
Take a break. Lie low.
This is not your arena anymore, Governor.
Mateo Ruiz is officially the governor now.
Don't lose yourself
in fighting a lost game,
or else, it'll be harder for you
to restore your reputation.
Darn it.
Excuse me, Governor.
Go ahead. Leave.
Papa, I see you're upset again.
I thought you had a meeting
with Mateo Ruiz.
Yes, I did, Papa.
But he refused my proposal.
That cave-dwelling troglodyte!
[suspenseful sting]
Who does he think he is?
You know, Emilia,
for the first time in history,
this province isn't governed
by an Ardiente.
I cannot take this!
You have to help me.
This can't be happening.
Why, Papa? Did you ever help me?
I had your case dismissed!
Come on, Papa!
I know the truth already.
It wasn't you who helped me out!
You know, the only reason
I am here in this house
is that I want to know
who my real mother is!
That's the truth, Papa!
Because only my mother can help me.
She alone and not you!
[dramatic tense music playing]
[exhales sharply]
[thuds]
I am Julio Ardiente! I am not nothing!
[breathing heavily]
As you all know, I was adopted.
But now, Ivy Aguas is dead.
From this day forward,
you will address me by my real name.
Lily Cruz.
[murmuring]
Is that understood?
-Yes, ma'am.
-Yes.
Have you finished your project
in Ardiente?
I'm starting another one.
What's next on the agenda?
Ms. Cruz, we need to set
a meeting with you
and Mrs. Helena Montoya.
Who's Helena Montoya?
She's the CEO of Montoya Industries,
and she's interested in investing
in our luxury residences project
in the suburbs.
She made a great offer.
Montoya Industries?
Never heard of it.
Don't set a meeting with Helena Montoya.
Not yet.
Instead, I want you
to research her company.
And you?
Do a background check
on this Helena Montoya.
Certainly, Ms. Cruz.
[opens, then closes drawer]
[unsettling music playing]
[line ringing]
Hello, Romulo.
I know you are there.
Come on, please.
I just want to know the truth.
Who told you to help me? Hello? Hello?!
-[line beeping]
-[exhales sharply]
[line ringing]
Hello, Attorney.
Can you tell me again the address
I asked you to research?
The one owned by Mercedes Palacio.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia] Who ordered you
to kidnap me? Huh?!
Who?! Answer me!
[Robert] I tracked down
the owner of the house
where those men brought you.
They're both registered
to one Mercedes Palacio.
Huh? Who is she?
[man] Ma'am.
Is Mercedes Palacio around?
Ma'am, I was told she rarely comes here.
[suspenseful music playing]
[car door closes]
Looking for me?
Mercedes Palacio?
Absolutely. Who else?
[suspenseful music intensifies]
My father keeps blaming me, when in fact,
he didn't lift a finger to help me.
Didn't you and Romulo save my life?
Why did you save me?
Is it because of my real mom?
Do you work for her? Is she your boss?
One at a time. You ask too many questions.
What's more important to you?
Becoming the queen of Ardiente,
or discovering your mom's identity?
[tense music playing]
Both.
I want to be the queen of Ardiente,
and have acting governor
Mateo Ruiz at my beck and call.
Are you up for it?
Is that all?
[suspenseful music playing]
Who are they?
[bodyguard grunts]
[screaming, grunting]
[thuds]
[suspenseful music playing]
Who are you?
Don't worry. We won't hurt you.
Do you work for Julio Ardiente?
[scoffs]
What do you want from me?
Someone wants to see you.
Who?
Red Dragon.
I'm sure the governor will love your plan.
Thanks, Diego.
[Mateo clears throat]
Governor.
Good afternoon.
Okay, shall we start?
Good morning, everyone.
-Today--
-[Mateo] Wait.
We can't start just yet.
Why, Governor? Looks like everyone's here.
We're still waiting for someone.
[tense music playing]
-Who?
-Me.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
Governor, is this a joke?!
Governor, I thought Lily Cruz
was aware that I'd be here
to give my opinion on her
little project for Ardiente.
After all, that's what
a consultant does, right?
Yes, you heard it right.
I am now the consultant
of Governor Mateo Ruiz.
I will help him with decisions
concerning this province.
What is this, Governor?
Are you kidding me?
Are you kidding me?!
Ms. Cruz,
why are you so surprised that
he got me as his consultant?
Have you forgotten?
I used to be the mayor
and the governor of this--
Yeah, right!
-Mayor Corrupt Queen,
-[suspenseful music playing]
and Governor Murderer
of Poblacion Ardiente!
Ms. Cruz, calm yourself!
Our province is already divided,
and this is the first step to peace.
For us to come and work together
for the progress of our province.
Exactly! We're divided
and we need to help one another
but what are you doing, Governor?!
What happened to you?!
Did these criminals threaten you?! Huh?!
Tell me, what did they do to you?
Did they hurt your family?
Is Julio behind this?
-What? Tell me--
-No!
I made this decision for
the betterment of our province!
We don't believe you.
Governor, you know the Ardientes.
You know they aren't capable of good.
You betrayed your promise to the people.
You made fools of us.
Governor Ruiz, we had
an agreement, remember?
We promised to help each other.
So, please. I'm telling you.
You don't have to be afraid
of the Ardientes!
Enough of this drama, Ms. Cruz.
Whether you like it or not,
I am now the consultant
of Governor Mateo Ruiz.
Meanwhile, you're just another nuisance
who wants a taste
of the governor's graces.
Well, I'm happy to say this.
I am here to protect the governor
from leeches like you!
You're the leech in this town!
You're sucking
Poblacion Ardiente's wealth!
You are the leech!
Well, guess what.
Whether you like it or not,
I get to decide for the governor.
And if I were you,
I'd be on my best behavior.
If you want to be in or out.
Not here.
[chuckles] Mm-mm.
[dramatic tense music playing]
[gloomy music playing]
[gloomy tense music playing]
Madam, here's the research you ordered.
[suspenseful music playing]
Ma'am, sir! It's Sir Arnaldo.
Why? What happened to my grandson?
Arnaldo?
-Arnaldo.
-[Emilia] Arnaldo.
Who are you?
We won't lose to the Ardientes.
We can take them on!
It's about time we let her know
that you're not to be messed with.
[beeping]
[Lily] At this point,
we shouldn't trust anyone.
We don't know who we're up against.
[beeping]
[theme music playing]